aboutkidshealth.ca 2006-06-17

# AboutKidsHealth: Privacy Policy

The AboutKidsHealth Web Site Privacy Policy

The Hospital for Sick Children (“Sick Kids”) has a set of rules, set out in Sick Kids’Privacy Policy, which addresses how it will deal with the privacy of personal and health information it acquires about its patients. AboutKidsHealth ([www.aboutkidshealth.ca](http://www.aboutkidshealth.ca/)) follows this policy. An overview of Sick Kids' Privacy Policy is set out in the following publication:

Information for Patients: [Protecting the privacy of your information at Sick Kids](http://www.sickkids.ca/familyinformation/custom/privacybooklet.pdf)

The Hospital for Sick Children Foundation has also published information which provides greater detail on how the Foundation uses personally identifiable information for fund raising purposes. Click [here](http://www.sickkids.on.ca/Foundation/section.asp?s=Who%2BWe%2BAre&sID=620&ss=Privacy&ssID=747&searchTerms=privacy) for more details. 

The following sets out Sick Kids' policy regarding information which is submitted from the various areas of the HSC Website (but excluding information submitted from the Sick Kids Foundation section of the Sick Kids Website or any information which is faxed or emailed to Sick Kids in response to information provided on the Sick Kids Website).

Personal Information

Personal information is any information that can be used to distinguish, identify or contact a specific individual. This information can include an individual's opinions or beliefs, as well as facts about, or related to, the individual. Business contact information and certain publicly available information, such as names, addresses and telephone numbers as published in telephone directories, are not considered personal information.

Collection

The Sick Kids Website allows visitors to provide comments using web forms which request a visitor’s email address. The web server utilized to operate the Sick Kids Website also creates a log of each visitor’s IP address, browser type, which documents were accessed and similar types of information. Sick Kids may utilize cookies on certain areas of the Sick Kids Website to provide continuity between Web pages.

Certain sections of the Sick Kids Website may also invite visitors to submit various types of information for various purposes. Sick Kids only collects personal information which is required for an identified purpose and limits collection to that information which is necessary for such purposes. All personal information will be collected by fair and lawful means.

Except where inappropriate, the knowledge and consent of the individual will be obtained for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information. Submission of personal information in response to a form provided on the Sick Kids Website shall be deemed to constitute deemed consent of the submitter to such collection, use or disclosure as is described in this policy and as otherwise described in the applicable portion of the Sick Kids Website.

Use, Disclosure and Retention of Personal Information

Sick Kids uses personal information collected from the Sick Kids Website to, as applicable, improve the operation of the Sick Kids Website, process a request and/or to respond to feedback. Any contact information submitted as part of a request to receive periodic email alerts or bulletins may also be used to send such alerts or bulletins.

Unless an “opt-out“ option is selected, contact information provided on an order submitted to the Specialty Food Shop may be used to send periodic information about products available but will not be disclosed to third parties (except service providers utilized for order fulfillment and/or customer service).

In the case of personal information submitted from the Careers Opportunities section of the Sick Kids Website, Sick Kids will use such information as part of an application for employment. Any such information may also be retained if the individual is hired for employment at Sick Kids or if Sick Kids is requested to retain such information for the purposes of considering such individual for future openings.

Sick Kids may utilize third party service providers to assist Sick Kids in carrying out the above mentioned purposes. With the exception of the above mentioned purposes and, of any disclosure to such third party service providers (who will be required to undertake to maintain the confidentiality of such information), Sick Kids will not use or further disclose any personally identifiable information collected from the Sick Kids Website without the consent of the individual or as may be permitted by law. Any such information collected from the Sick Kids Website will be retained only for as long as necessary for the fulfillment of the applicable purposes.

One of the privacy principles followed by Sick Kids is to ensure that personal information collected from the Sick Kids Website will be as accurate, complete and up-to-date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used. Most of the purposes for which information is collected on the Sick Kids Website do not reasonably require that Sick Kids confirm or maintain the accuracy or currency of the information submitted.

Security safeguards, appropriate to the sensitivity of the information, will be used to protect personal information.

Openness, Access and Accountability

Sick Kids will make readily available to individuals specific information about its policies and practices relating to the management of personal information collected from the Sick Kids Website. Upon request, but except as may be restricted by law, an individual will be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of his or her personal information and will be given reasonable access to that information. Such access may be subject to reimbursement of reasonable costs incurred by Sick Kids to comply with any such access request. An individual will be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the personal information applicable to such individual and have it amended as appropriate.

Sick Kids assumes responsibility for personal information under its custody and control which is collected from the Sick Kids Website. If you have any questions, concerns or complaints regarding Sick Kids' privacy policy please contact our Privacy Officer:

Privacy Office

The Hospital for Sick Children  
555 University Avenue  
Toronto, Ontario M5G 1X8  

E-mail: privacy.office@sickkids.ca  
Phone: 416-813-7474  

Sick Kids updates its privacy policies from time to time. Please check back periodically for updates to the above information.

Back To Top >
